Let's think a little bit about the molecule sodium chloride.
دعونا نفكر قليلا عن الجزيء الصوديوم كلوريد &quot; .
If we look at the periodic table right over here,
اذا نظرنا في الدوري هنا , الطاولة
we see that sodium is a Group 1 element.
نري ان الصوديوم العنصر الاول هو مجموعة .
It's an alkali metal.
انها alkali المعدن .
It has one valence electron.
لديه التكافؤ الكترون واحد .
It's also not too electronegative.
انها ليست كذلك ايضا electronegative .
It's sitting here on the left-hand side
انها تجلس هنا على الجانب الايسر
of the periodic table.
من الجدول الدوري .
We know the general trend for electronegativity
نحن نعرف ان المنحى العام لelectronegativity
is that it increases as we go to the top right.
انها زيادة ك ذهبنا الى القمة .
So these elements over here generally
لذا هذه العناصر هنا عموما
like to hog electrons.
ان hog الالكترونات .
These elements over here generally
هذه العناصر هنا عموما
like to give away electrons.
ان نعطي الالكترونات .
These are electropositive, these are electronegative.
هذه هي electropositive , هذه هي electronegative .
So sodium right over here, with its one valence electron,
لذا الصوديوم هنا , التكافؤ واحد , الالكترون معها
it's a very good candidate for giving away an electron.
انه مرشح جيدة جدا الالكترون لاعطاء بعيدا .
On the other side of the periodic table,
على الجانب الاخر من الجدول الدوري .
we have chlorine right over here.
لدينا chlorine هنا .
It's a Group 7 element.
انها مجموعة 7 العنصر .
It's a halogen.
انها halogen .
It would love nothing more than to gain an electron so that it
الحب ليس اكثر منه لذا ان تكسبه الالكترون
can get to the magic number of eight valence electrons.
يمكن ان تصل الى عدد السحر من ثمانية التكافؤ الالكترونات .
It is very electronegative.
انها electronegative جدا .
So what you can imagine would happen
لذا ما يمكن تخيلوا ما سيحدث
is that if these two things were to interact?
اذا هذه الاشياء للتفاعل ?
The chlorine would nab sodium's extra electron over here,
وسnab الصوديوم chlorineه هنا , الالكترون اضافية
and it would become the chloride anion.
وستصبح وanion كلوريد &quot; .
And then sodium would become the sodium cation.
ومن ثم سالصوديوم اصبح الصوديوم cation .
Cation just is a positive ion.
فقط في الايون cation ايجابية .
Anion is just a negative ion.
هو فقط anion ايون سلبي .
And so this one right over here is now positive.
وهذا صحيح هنا الان .
Sodium is now positive.
الان الصوديوم ايجابية .
Chloride is a negative ion.
هو كلوريد &quot; ايون سلبي .
And so they're going to be attracted to each other,
ولذلك سيكون ولبعضهم البعض ,
and they're going to form this ionic bond.
وس هذا الشكل ionic بوند .